<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes on Rich Youngkin</title>
    <link>https://youngkin.github.io/categories/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Rich Youngkin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:06:44 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://youngkin.github.io/categories/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Application Monitoring on a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/kuberenetes-application-monitoring-on-a-reaspberry-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:06:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/kuberenetes-application-monitoring-on-a-reaspberry-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Andres Dallimonti on Unsplash
 The full text of this article can be found on Medium  This article is about monitoring applications deployed to a Kubernetes cluster running on Raspberry Pis, specifically the monitoring infrastructure.
It’s important to note that while the focus of this article is the Raspberry Pi platform, much of what’s described, except for the ARM specific areas, is applicable to other hardware platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Kubernetes Ingress on a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/install-kuberenetes-ingress-on-a-raspberry-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:05:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/install-kuberenetes-ingress-on-a-raspberry-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Tianshu Liu on Unsplash
 The full text of this article can be found on Medium  This is the fourth article in the series described in Develop and Deploy Kubernetes Applications on a Raspberry Pi Cluster. The previous article described how to install Kubernetes on a Raspberry Pi cluster. This article is about Kubernetes Ingress. The next article, Kubernetes Application Monitoring on a Raspberry Pi Cluster, covers setting up Prometheus, Grafana, and a Elasticsearch, Fluentd, and Kibana (EFK) stack on the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Kubernetes on a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/install-kubernetes-on-a-respberry-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:04:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/install-kubernetes-on-a-respberry-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Flavio Gasperini on Unsplash
 The full text of this article can be found on Medium  This is the third article in the series described in Develop and Deploy Kubernetes Applications on a Raspberry Pi Cluster. The previous article covered setting up a Raspberry Pi cluster. The next article is How to Install Kubernetes Ingress on a Raspberry Pi Cluster.
This article is where the rubber meets the road, getting a fully operational, multi-node, Kubernetes cluster up and running on a Raspberry Pi cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop and Deploy Kubernetes Applications on a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/develop_and_deploy_kubernetes_applications_on_a_raspberry_pi_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 01:01:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/develop_and_deploy_kubernetes_applications_on_a_raspberry_pi_cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Want to set up a Kubernetes lab, but don&amp;rsquo;t want use Minikube or spend a lot of money on hardware. This is the first post in a series that describes how to set up a complete Kubernetes cluster on a cluster of Raspberry Pis. This will include topics such as setting up a logging infrastructure, monitoring, Ingress, and other platform level capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>