<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MySQL on Rich Youngkin&#39;s software engineering blog</title>
    <link>https://youngkin.github.io/tags/mysql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MySQL on Rich Youngkin&#39;s software engineering blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:07:25 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://youngkin.github.io/tags/mysql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install MariaDB on a Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/how-to-install-mariadb-an-a-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:07:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/how-to-install-mariadb-an-a-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>This article covers how to install and configure MariaDB, a feature-equivalent alternative to MySQL, on a Raspberry Pi. Installing is relatively straightforward. Configuring the database is somewhat more involved but still quite manageable.
The full text of this article can be found on Medium  This is the sixth and final article in the Develop and Deploy Kubernetes Applications on a Raspberry Pi Cluster series. It marks the transition from a purely Raspberry Pi focus to software development more generally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop and Deploy Kubernetes Applications on a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/develop_and_deploy_kubernetes_applications_on_a_raspberry_pi_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 01:01:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/develop_and_deploy_kubernetes_applications_on_a_raspberry_pi_cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Want to set up a Kubernetes lab, but don&amp;rsquo;t want use Minikube or spend a lot of money on hardware. This is the first post in a series that describes how to set up a complete Kubernetes cluster on a cluster of Raspberry Pis. This will include topics such as setting up a logging infrastructure, monitoring, Ingress, and other platform level capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>