<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raspberry Pi on Rich Youngkin</title>
    <link>https://youngkin.github.io/tags/raspberry-pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Raspberry Pi on Rich Youngkin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 13:13:42 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://youngkin.github.io/tags/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi GPIO in Go and C - RGB LED</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/sunfoundergpionotesrgbled/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 13:13:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/sunfoundergpionotesrgbled/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi GPIO in Go and C - Blinking LED</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/sunfoundergpionotesled/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 13:13:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/sunfoundergpionotesled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first article in a series that explores GPIO programming on a Raspberry Pi 3B+. You can find the full series &lt;a href=&#34;../../categories/gpio&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It is a supplement to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.sunfounder.com/projects/raphael-kit/en/latest/1.1.1_blinking_led_c.html&#34;&gt;Sunfounder Blinking LED project&lt;/a&gt;. The code samples will be in Go and C.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulse Width Modulation for Dummies</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/pulsewidthmodulationraspberrypi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 13:13:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/pulsewidthmodulationraspberrypi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article provides some details about hardware and software based PWM on the Raspberry Pi, specifically the 3B+ with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org/app/uploads/2012/02/BCM2835-ARM-Peripherals.pdf&#34;&gt;Broadcomm BCM2835 board&lt;/a&gt;. This article has an accompanying application, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/youngkin/gpio&#34;&gt;PWM Explorer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, that can be used to experiment with PWM settings and capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install MariaDB on a Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/how-to-install-mariadb-an-a-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:07:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/how-to-install-mariadb-an-a-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>This article covers how to install and configure MariaDB, a feature-equivalent alternative to MySQL, on a Raspberry Pi. Installing is relatively straightforward. Configuring the database is somewhat more involved but still quite manageable.
The full text of this article can be found on Medium  This is the sixth and final article in the Develop and Deploy Kubernetes Applications on a Raspberry Pi Cluster series. It marks the transition from a purely Raspberry Pi focus to software development more generally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Application Monitoring on a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/kuberenetes-application-monitoring-on-a-reaspberry-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:06:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/kuberenetes-application-monitoring-on-a-reaspberry-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Andres Dallimonti on Unsplash
 The full text of this article can be found on Medium  This article is about monitoring applications deployed to a Kubernetes cluster running on Raspberry Pis, specifically the monitoring infrastructure.
It’s important to note that while the focus of this article is the Raspberry Pi platform, much of what’s described, except for the ARM specific areas, is applicable to other hardware platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Kubernetes Ingress on a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/install-kuberenetes-ingress-on-a-raspberry-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:05:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/install-kuberenetes-ingress-on-a-raspberry-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Tianshu Liu on Unsplash
 The full text of this article can be found on Medium  This is the fourth article in the series described in Develop and Deploy Kubernetes Applications on a Raspberry Pi Cluster. The previous article described how to install Kubernetes on a Raspberry Pi cluster. This article is about Kubernetes Ingress. The next article, Kubernetes Application Monitoring on a Raspberry Pi Cluster, covers setting up Prometheus, Grafana, and a Elasticsearch, Fluentd, and Kibana (EFK) stack on the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Kubernetes on a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/install-kubernetes-on-a-respberry-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:04:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/install-kubernetes-on-a-respberry-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Flavio Gasperini on Unsplash
 The full text of this article can be found on Medium  This is the third article in the series described in Develop and Deploy Kubernetes Applications on a Raspberry Pi Cluster. The previous article covered setting up a Raspberry Pi cluster. The next article is How to Install Kubernetes Ingress on a Raspberry Pi Cluster.
This article is where the rubber meets the road, getting a fully operational, multi-node, Kubernetes cluster up and running on a Raspberry Pi cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/how_to_set_up_a_raspberry_pi_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:01:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/how_to_set_up_a_raspberry_pi_cluster/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Jonathan on Unsplash
 The full text of this article can be found on Medium.  This article covers what you need to know to setup your own Raspberry Pi cluster, including you what you need to buy, how to install the OS and configure the Raspberry Pis, how to set up networking, and other things you need to know to sinplify ongoing administration and maintenance of the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop and Deploy Kubernetes Applications on a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/develop_and_deploy_kubernetes_applications_on_a_raspberry_pi_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 01:01:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/develop_and_deploy_kubernetes_applications_on_a_raspberry_pi_cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Want to set up a Kubernetes lab, but don&amp;rsquo;t want use Minikube or spend a lot of money on hardware. This is the first post in a series that describes how to set up a complete Kubernetes cluster on a cluster of Raspberry Pis. This will include topics such as setting up a logging infrastructure, monitoring, Ingress, and other platform level capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>