<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Traefik on Rich Youngkin</title>
    <link>https://youngkin.github.io/tags/traefik/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Traefik on Rich Youngkin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:05:37 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://youngkin.github.io/tags/traefik/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Kubernetes Ingress on a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/install-kuberenetes-ingress-on-a-raspberry-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:05:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/install-kuberenetes-ingress-on-a-raspberry-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Tianshu Liu on Unsplash
 The full text of this article can be found on Medium  This is the fourth article in the series described in Develop and Deploy Kubernetes Applications on a Raspberry Pi Cluster. The previous article described how to install Kubernetes on a Raspberry Pi cluster. This article is about Kubernetes Ingress. The next article, Kubernetes Application Monitoring on a Raspberry Pi Cluster, covers setting up Prometheus, Grafana, and a Elasticsearch, Fluentd, and Kibana (EFK) stack on the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop and Deploy Kubernetes Applications on a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://youngkin.github.io/post/develop_and_deploy_kubernetes_applications_on_a_raspberry_pi_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 01:01:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngkin.github.io/post/develop_and_deploy_kubernetes_applications_on_a_raspberry_pi_cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Want to set up a Kubernetes lab, but don&amp;rsquo;t want use Minikube or spend a lot of money on hardware. This is the first post in a series that describes how to set up a complete Kubernetes cluster on a cluster of Raspberry Pis. This will include topics such as setting up a logging infrastructure, monitoring, Ingress, and other platform level capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>